Finding Aid for Walter Jarocki Photographs, 1937, 1948, 1952-1959, 1970s-early 1980s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Walter Jarocki photographs 1937, 1948, 1952-1959, 1970s-early 1980s
Jarocki, Walter.
2 prints (in oversize folder)
(in 3 boxes)
2265 negatives (approximate
Hamtramck, Michigan, commercial photographer who took photographs for the city during the administration of Mayor Albert J. Zak in the 1950s. Photonegatives, mostly dated between 1952 and 1958, of public work projects (such as laying of sidewalks), ceremonial functions (such as Christmas displays on city streets), and some political activities. The collection also includes views of the city, its downtown area, residential streets and alleyways behind residences. There are two photographs of Frank Murphy (approximately 1937) and Harry Truman (approximately 1948) visiting Hamtramck. Also a smaller group of photonegatives from the 1970s-early 1980s depicting activities of mayor Robert W. Kozaren, his office, and Hamtramck's daily life.
969 Aa 2; UAs
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Judge Don Binkowski (donor no. 5501 ) and came to the library in January 1987.
The collection is open to research.
Walter "Flash" Jarocki was commercial photographer and the Hamtramck, Michigan. He served in the Coast Guard during World War II, then spent 20 years with the Hamtramck Fire Department, 6 of them as the Fire Marshall. In the 1950s he photographed and reported for the Hamtramck's newspaper The Citizen and for the mayor's office. In 1960 Jarocki moved to Tarpon Springs, Florida. In 1972-1980s he worked as a reporter and photographer for Tampa's WTVT television station.
One of his most important clients in the 1950s was the city of Hamtramck itself: its citizens, businesses, schools, and its leaders, such as mayor Albert J. Zak. Albert Zak, "the man with the plan for Hamtramck," was elected mayor in 1952 on promises of better recreation and health programs, slum clearance, more jobs, and clean streets and alleys. Zak opposed loans and raises for city employees, while financing continuous street-sweeping and paving of city alleys at the expense of the pension fund. In 1963 Zak took an appointment with Wayne County and resigned as Hamtramck's Mayor. He was re-elected mayor in 1974, having appealed to voters' desire for stability on the campaign trail, but died in office the following year. In the 1950s Jarocki took hundreds of photographs during Zak's administration, chronicling the official activities of the mayor and the accomplishments of the city government. Jarocki also took photographs of Hamtramck's citizens, sports teams, businesses, public events, street views, etc. for the Hamtramck Citizen newspaper.
In 1980 Robert W. Kozaren was elected the Hamtramck mayor, to become the longest-served mayor in the city's history (1980-1997). During Kozaren's tenure a General Motors assembly plant was built in Hamtramck, as well as the William Dickerson Detention Facility. The city also gained in population in the 1990s.
The Walter "Flash" Jarocki photograph collection includes photonegatives and two oversize photoprints and organized into three series: Walter "Flash" Jarocki, "Gordie," and Unknown photographer.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Jarocki, Walter.; Alleys--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Baseball--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Basketball--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Christmas decorations.; Floods--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Hamtramck (Mich.)--Alleys.; Hamtramck (Mich.)--Floods.; Hamtramck (Mich.)--Refuse disposal.; Hamtramck (Mich.)--Streets.; Kozaren, Robert W.; Mayors--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Municipal government--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Polish Americans--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Refuse and refuse disposal--Michigan--Hamtramck.; School children--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Streets--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Rogers, Roy, 1911-1998; Zak, Albert J.
Genre Terms:
Negatives (photographic); Photographs.
- Walter "Flash" Jarocki
  The Walter "Flash" Jarocki series (approximately 2265 photonegatives and 2 oversize photoprints; 1937, 1948 and 1952-1959) is the heart of the collection. The majority of images taken by Jarocki are those of mayor Zak at public events and a number of private gatherings; also images depicting Hamtramck public work projects, ceremonial functions, athletic events, political campaigns, public meetings and social gatherings. The series includes numerous views of the city, its downtown area, residential streets, and alleyways behind the residences. A number of images depict the city of Milan, Mich. leaders, events, and images. Also found in the series are two photoprints, one of an earlier date featuring Frank Murphy shaking hands with Mayor Rudolph Tenerowicz, most likely taken in 1937; the other is a photograph of President Truman, probably taken during the 1948 campaign, and being greeted by Hamtramck dignitaries. Photonegatives in this series are stored in original envelopes with descriptions of events, names of people, date, and time(s) of the day when images were taken. Container list in this finding aid reflects only main subject of images. Researchers may find more detailed descriptions on envelopes.
  - Governor Frank Murphy shaking hands with Hamtramck mayor Rudolph Tenerowicz 1937; President Harry S. Truman campaigning with Mayor Stephen Skrzycki, 1948 (Folder 1)
  - 1952
    - April 15, 1952
      - Inaugural of City officials; Copernicus School (Box 1)
    - July 30, 1952
      - Mayor Zak (Box 1)
    - August 16, 1952
      - Chester Upholstering (Box 1)
    - September 8, 1952
      - Blood donation, red Cross Detroit chapter; a group photo (Box 1)
      - Hamtramck Department of Public Works trucks (Box 1)
  - 1953
    - January 10, 1953
      - Slum clearance (older homes, buildings, and properties) (Box 1)
    - January 12, 1953
      - Metropolitan Club installation (Box 1)
    - July 8, 1953
      - Street scenes and views (Box 1)
    - July 10, 1953
      - Dirty alleys; Mayor A.J. Zak beginning demolition of old building (Box 1)
    - July 19, 1953
      - Slum clearance (older homes, buildings, and properties) (Box 1)
    - August 3 and 4 1953
      - Mayor Zak and others; workers punching in (Box 1)
    - August 27 and 31 1957
      - Mayor Zak cutting ragweed; Mayor Zak and others (Box 1)
    - September 2-6, 1953
      - Hydrant (Box 1)
      - Mrs. Alex Banas (Box 1)
      - Picnic (Box 1)
    - November 30, 1953
      - Thom McAnn, Woody, Mayor, Kolowich, with Christmas decorations (Box 1)
    - December 2, 1953
      - Christmas decorations being installed along Joseph Campau Avenue (Box 1)
    - December 15, 1953
      - Salt spreaders being used after first snow of the season (Box 1)
    - December 30, 1953
      - Mayor's office; Christmas tree (Box 1)
    - January 8, 1954
      - Men examining one-way signs at corner of Joseph Campau Avenue and Trowbridge (Box 1)
    - January 9, 1954
      - Men taking out petition for Mayor Zak (Box 1)
    - January 11, 1954
      - Fraternal Order of Police installation; Mayor Zak (Box 1)
    - January 15, 1954
      - Mayor Zak and Office of Civil Defense truck (Box 1)
    - February 1, 1954
      - City light poles along Hamtramck street (Box 1)
    - February 3, 1954
      - Various street views of Hamtramck (Box 1)
    - February 10, 1954
      - Group of ladies; safety patrol (envelope includes 2 group photos depicting ladies and gentlemen) (Box 1)
    - February 28, 1954
      - Mayor Zak at UAW, Local #3 meeting and demonstration (Box 1)
    - March 3, 1954
      - Board of Review (Box 1)
      - Catholic war veterans (Box 1)
    - March 8, 1954
      - Civil Service (Box 1)
    - March 12, 1954
      - Hanging of flags along Joseph Campau (preliminary to parade?); stop signs and stop sign installation (Box 1)
    - March 14, 1954
      - Signatures collecting (Box 1)
    - March 20, 1954
      - Mayor Zak birthday (Box 1)
    - March 21, 1954
      - Installation of Hamtramck Police Reserve (Box 1)
    - March 25, 1954
      - C. Lubelt birthday party (Box 1)
    - March 26, 1954
      - William Kozerski; Post 4404 V.F.W. at Pulaski School (Box 1)
      - Judy Kozak (Box 1)
    - March 27, 1954
      - Mayor Zak at Democratic Club (Box 1)
    - April 5, 1954
      - Mayor's office after elections (Box 1)
    - April 13, 1954
      - Copernicus High School; inauguration of city officials (Box 1)
    - April 19, 1954
      - Dodge overpass (Box 1)
    - May 5, 1954
      - Mayor Zak with Mayor King of Milan, Mich. (Box 1)
    - May 14, 1954
      - Milan, Mich. Kiwanis Club at Mayor Zak's office (Box 1)
    - May 18, 1954
      - St. Ladislaus Church at Mayor Zak's office (Box 1)
    - May 19, 1954
      - Stanley and Bill Kozicki, Bill Kozerski (Box 1)
    - May 21, 1954
      - Property along Joseph Campau (for development?) (Box 1)
    - My 27 1954
      - Hamtramck Little League opening at Memorial Park (images of Mayor Zak) (Box 1)
    - June 8, 1954
      - Mayor Zak with child; Mayor with Bowling League (Box 1)
    - June 14, 1954
      - Post 4404 Veterans of Foreign Wars and Auxiliary Police (Box 1)
    - June 23, 1954
      - Copies of Hamtramck Allied Veterans Council; Mayor's painting (Box 1)
    - July 4, 1954
      - Couple in their backyard relaxing on the Fourth of July (Box 1)
    - July 18, 1954
      - Municipal League picnic (Box 1)
    - July 20, 1954
      - Mayor Zak, Kaufman, H. Adamczyk (Box 1)
    - July 31, 1954
      - Philip A. Hart, candidate for Lieutenant Governor, and Mayor Zak campaigning (Box 1)
    - August 7, 1954
      - Mayor Zak and others (Box 1)
    - August 11, 1954
      - Mayor Zak with Mayor McPherson and others (Box 1)
    - August 18, 1954
      - Max's Jewelry; Rotary Club (Box 1)
    - August 24, 1954
      - Men laying sidewalk along residential street (Box 1)
    - August 25, 1954
      - Mayor Zak portrait (Box 1)
    - September 1, 1954
      - Polish Kitchen at State Fair (Box 1)
    - September 3, 1954
      - Commissioner William B. Malinowski (Box 1)
    - September 8 (?) 1954
      - Street signs near Roosevelt and Joseph Campau Avenue in Hamtramck (Box 1)
    - September 20, 1954
      - Mayor Zak, Ed. Banas, S. Czarnecki reading proclamation (Box 1)
    - September 24, 1954
      - Detroit Yacht Club (Box 1)
    - October 8, 1954
      - Alpena dump and Hamtramck alleys (Box 1)
    - October 10, 1954
      - St. Ladislaus football game at Key Worth (Box 1)
    - October 11, 1954
      - Hamtramck alleys and signal lights (Box 1)
    - October 14, 1954
      - Pouring of cement at salt shelter; street views; dog warden vehicle (Box 1)
    - November 7, 1954
      - Viaduct (Box 1)
    - November 9, 1954
      - Dodge City Day press conference in Hamtramck (Box 1)
    - November 13, 1954
      - Beauty Queen; Lee Barecki at Woody's (Box 1)
    - November 14, 1954
      - Beauty Queen; Lee Barecki at Dodge Brothers (Box 1)
      - Wider St; Dodge's (Box 1)
    - November 16, 1954
      - Car presentation and Dodge City Day parade (Box 1)
    - November 17, 1954
      - Roy Rogers in Hamtramck for Dodge City Day festivities (Box 1)
    - November 15, 1954
      - All municipal mayors or representatives for Queen Agency (Box 1)
    - November 16, 1954
      - Car presentation and parade; Mayor Zak (Box 1)
    - November 17, 1954
      - Roy Rodgers at Dodge City Day (Box 1)
    - November 19, 1954
      - Queen, Lee Barecki, and others (Box 1)
      - Dave Stober; prizes (Box 1)
      - Mayor Zak and Mayor King of Milan, Mich. (Box 1)
      - Union (Box 1)
    - November 21, 1954
      - Queen at football game (Box 1)
    - November 23, 1954
      - Dave Stober; Beauty Queen (Box 1)
    - December 3, 1954
      - Mayor Zak and others at sale at Woody (Box 1)
    - December 7, 1954
      - Christmas tree decorators (Box 1)
      - Lighting of Christmas tree (Box 1)
      - New policemen (Box 1)
    - December 14, 1954
      - Football players banquet (Box 1)
    - December 15, 1954
      - Nativity scenes in park (Box 1)
    - December 22, 1954
      - Nativity scenes in park (Box 1)
    - December 30, 1954
      - Mayor Zak; Fair Employment Practices Committee (Box 1)
  - 1955
    - January 7, 1955
      - Christmas decorations along Joseph Campau Avenue (Box 2)
    - January 9, 1955
      - Christmas lights at night (Box 2)
    - January 28, 1955
      - Policemen sworn in (Box 2)
    - March 7, 1955
      - Board of review (Box 2)
    - March 10, 1955
      - Josephine Liski (8 years old) (Box 2)
    - March 31, 1955
      - Police Department, new officers (Box 2)
    - April 2, 1955
      - Presentation of trophy (Box 2)
    - April 18, 1955
      - Mayor Zak and others (Box 2)
    - April 20, 1955
      - Chief Walter Jaros testimonial (Box 2)
    - April 22, 1955
      - St. Ladislaus Bowling Club; trophy presentation (Box 2)
    - April 28, 1955
      - Citizen Open House (Box 2)
    - April 28, 1955
      - Citizen opening (Box 2)
    - May 3, 1955
      - Mayor Zak, the Lions (Box 2)
      - New Chief car (Box 2)
    - June 18, 1955
      - Dorothy Mlynarek, Richard Zak (Box 2)
      - Zak Mlynarak wedding (Box 2)
    - June 19, 1955
      - Al Zak birthday party (Box 2)
    - July 5, 1955
      - New Library ground breaking (Box 2)
    - August 15, 1955
      - Madonna College sisters and Mayor Zak (Box 2)
    - August 23, 1955
      - Dedication of new firing range (Box 2)
    - August 30, 1955
      - Chas. Zulkowski's promotion to Sergeant (Box 2)
    - August 31, 1955
      - State Fair Polish Kitchen (Box 2)
    - September 1, 1955
      - State Fair Polish Hut (Box 2)
    - September 12, 1955
      - Recruiting trophy (Box 2)
    - September 26, 1955
      - Workmen laying sidewalks on Sobieski (Box 2)
    - October 3, 1955
      - Hamtramck Library fund raising (Box 2)
    - October 11, 1955
      - Archbishop Gawlina at St. Florian (Box 2)
    - October 20, 1955
      - Hamtramck Chess Club at City Hall (Box 2)
    - October 28, 1955
      - Workmen repairing curbs to Hamtramck street (Box 2)
    - November 3, 1955
      - Hamtramck Recreation Department (Box 2)
    - November 5, 1955
      - Curb work along residential street (Box 2)
    - December 6, 1955
      - Mayor A.J. Zak portraits (Box 2)
    - December 8, 1955
      - Christmas display at Memorial Park (Box 2)
    - December 14, 1955
      - Christmas decorations along Joseph Campau (Box 2)
  - 1956
    - January 1, 1956
      - Home owners installations (Box 2)
    - January 9, 1955
      - Inspection of Library Committee (Box 2)
    - January 20, 1956
      - Storeroom with city (?) records and individuals (Bielski) burning them (Box 2)
    - February 7, 1955
      - Boy Scouts at City Hall (Box 2)
    - February 15, 1956
      - Mayor Zak and Ed. Kondrat (Box 2)
    - March 2, 1956
      - Mary Zak and Marlene Serwatka (12 years old) (Box 2)
    - March 21, 1956
      - Mayor Zak birthday; Department heads (Box 2)
    - April 10, 1956
      - Inauguration of elected officials for 1956-1958 (Box 2)
    - April 24, 1956
      - Veterans; poppy sale to girls (Box 2)
    - May 8, 1956
      - Government Day at St. Florian (Box 2)
    - June 23, 1956
      - Library staff and building (Box 2)
    - July 1, 1956
      - Hamtramck Library dedication (Box 2)
    - September 10, 1956
      - T.B. survey (Box 2)
    - September 16, 1956
      - Promotions (Box 2)
    - October 2, 1956
      - New policemen (Box 2)
    - October 9, 1956
      - Street sign; St. Francis Hospital (Box 2)
    - October 12, 1956
      - Little League (Box 2)
    - October 22, 1956
      - Signing incinerator contract (Box 2)
    - October 29, 1956
      - X-Ray office (Box 2)
    - November 6, 1956
      - Kiwanis Club (Box 2)
    - November 7, 1956
      - Crowning of queen at St. Florian (Box 2)
    - November 12, 1956
      - Cub Scouts from St. Florian (Box 2)
    - November 23, 1956
      - Lesinski; Christmas cards (Box 2)
    - Undated 1956
      - Dodge automobile facility and other street views (Box 2)
  - 1957
    - January 10, 1957
      - Mayor Zak receiving new Dodge from Leo George (Box 2)
    - January 30, 1957
      - Presentation of charcoal portrait to Library (Box 2)
    - February 5, 1957
      - Boy Scout week (Box 2)
    - February 10, 1957
      - St. Florian Father (Box 2)
    - February 11, 1957
      - Lee Barecki (Box 2)
    - February 21, 1957
      - Ground breaking for incinerator (Box 2)
    - March 21, 1957
      - Al Zak birthday party (Box 2)
    - March 25, 1957
      - Imperial Bar (Box 2)
    - April 10, 1957
      - Broken-down equipment; dirty alleys (Box 2)
    - April 23, 1957
      - Lions first cane taken (Box 2)
    - May 1, 1957
      - Pouring cement at incinerator (Box 2)
    - May 2, 1957
      - Poppy sale at Mayor's office (Box 2)
    - May 6, 1957
      - Poppy sales (Box 2)
    - May 16, 1957
      - Chester-Pierce fence (Box 2)
    - July 5, 1957
      - Promotions (Box 2)
    - July 19, 1957
      - New rubbish and garbage cans; alley views (Box 2)
    - August 19, 1957
      - Celia Atma and Clarence Lubelt with awards (Box 2)
    - September 13, 1957
      - New policemen (Box 2)
    - September 17, 1957
      - Bill Brooks and sailors (Box 2)
      - Prime Minister in Exile Antoni Pajak and Al Zak (Box 2)
    - September 19, 1957
      - Birthday cake at Citizen (Box 2)
    - October 12, 1957
      - Older properties along Wyandotte Ave. (Box 2)
    - October 20, 1957
      - Homecoming football game (Box 2)
    - November 16, 1957
      - Shoppers Free Ride (Box 2)
    - November 20 and 24 1957
      - New truck chassis (Box 2)
    - December 7, 1957
      - Shoppers Free Ride (Box 2)
    - December 12, 1957
      - Christmas tree lighting at park (Box 2)
    - December 27, 1957
      - Petitioners (Box 2)
  - 1958
    - January 21, 1958
      - Ukrainian organization at Mayor's office (Box 2)
    - January 26, 1958
      - Knights of Columbus ground breaking (Box 2)
    - February 8, 1958
      - Children going to the Hamtramck Public Library (Box 2)
      - Tree trimming (Box 2)
    - March 20, 1958
      - Mayor Zak's birthday party (Box 2)
    - April 22, 1958
      - Inaugural of Hamtramck officers, Copernicus Hall (Box 2)
    - May 1, 1958
      - Navy recruiting station (Box 2)
    - May 17, 1958
      - Garbage cans (new and old) (Box 2)
    - May 23, 1958
      - Alpena dump in Hamtramck (Box 2)
    - June 30, 1958
      - Dodge Breakfast (Box 2)
    - July 8, 1958
      - Slum clearance; meeting at Mayor's office (Box 2)
    - July 15, 1958
      - Drain Commissioner Herrick and Mayor Zak at City Hall (Box 2)
    - August 1, 1958
      - Citizen staff (Box 2)
    - August 6, 1958
      - Flooded streets (Conant Ave. and Joseph Campau) in Hamtramck (Box 2)
    - August 12, 1958
      - Mayor Zak and planning consultants (Box 2)
    - September 19, 1958
      - Safety Award (Box 2)
    - September 26, 1958
      - Polish editor of People's republic and Mayor Zak (Box 2)
    - October 12, 1958
      - Knights of Columbus Cardinal Mercier Council No. 2723 (Box 2)
    - October 15, 1958
      - Portrait presentation (Box 2)
  - 1959
    - March 18, 1959
      - Mayor Zak's birthday party (Box 2)
    - June 4, 1959
      - UAW-Local #3 (Box 2)
    - June 26, 1959
      - Acting Mayor Rooks and Acting Council President Kozerski (Box 2)
    - June 28, 1959
      - Metropolitan Airport (Box 2)
    - September 2, 1959
      - Safety Award for Hamtramck Schools (Box 2)
    - September 29, 1959
      - Mayor Zak and Auxiliary Firemen (Box 2)
  - Undated (Box 3)
    - At Milan, Mich.; Mayor for a Day (May 5, 195-?) (Box 3)
    - Back alley (Box 3)
    - Baseball game (Box 3)
    - Building interior (Box 3)
    - Couples (Box 3)
    - Exteriors of buildings (Box 3)
    - Fire hydrant (Box 3)
    - Fredricks (Box 3)
    - Garbage cans and removal, 2 envelopes (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck quota (Box 3)
    - Landscaping (Box 3)
    - Lottery, 5 negatives (Box 3)
    - Mayor Zak
      - Group photos (Box 3)
      - On fire truck (Box 3)
      - Shaking hands (Box 3)
      - Signing documents (Box 3)
      - With handicapped children (Box 3)
    - Milan Fire Department truck (Box 3)
    - Parked cars (Box 3)
    - Policemen (Box 3)
    - Portraits (Box 3)
    - Public events, 2 envelopes (Box 3)
    - Road works (Box 3)
    - School children crossing the street (Box 3)
    - Street cleaning (Box 3)
    - Street light (Box 3)
    - Street signs (Box 3)
    - Street views (Box 3)
    - Tree works (Box 3)
    - Unidentified event, prisoner's uniform (Box 3)
    - Unidentified meeting (Box 3)
    - Women cooking, men eating (Box 3)
    - Flash Jarocki's business card (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- "Gordie," 1970s-1980s
  - St. Ladislaus basketball game March 1971 (Box 3)
  - Untitled Envelope 1
    - Couples seating outside, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Demolition site, 5 negatives (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck's anniversary (Box 3)
    - Knights of Columbus ceremony, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Kowalski sausage (Mayor Kozaren), 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Mayor Robert Kozaren's office (Box 3)
    - Mayor Robert Kozaren with unidentified (Box 3)
    - Office workers, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Young people taking notes (Box 3)
  - Untitled Envelope 2
    - Hamtramck Chancellors football game, 11 negatives (Box 3)
    - School children, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Unidentified girl, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Woods, 2 negatives (Box 3)
  - Untitled Envelope 3
    - Bank of Commerce open house (Box 3)
    - Car accident on freeway, 4 negatives (Box 3)
    - Christmas, 3 negatives (Box 3)
    - Planting a tree, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Shifrin Willens Jewelers, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - St. Ladislaus basketball game, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Storefronts, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Unidentified, 3 negatives (Box 3)
    - Unidentified group (Box 3)
  - Untitled Envelope 4
    - Group portraits, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Individual portraits, 3 negatives (Box 3)
    - License plates, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Snow shoveling, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Street views, 5 negatives (Box 3)
    - Wedding, 4 negatives (Box 3)
- Unknown photographer 1970s-1980s
  The "Gordie" series (approximately 100 photonegatives; 1970s-1980s) takes its name from the name "Gordie" inscribed across five envelopes. One of the original envelopes was titled and dated "St. Ladislaus basketball game, March 1971"; the rest of the envelopes are numbered as they were found in the collection (Envelopes 1-4). Researchers will find description of subjects of photonegatives in these envelopes in the container list. Untitled and undated photonegatives in envelopes 1-4 depict Hamtramck's daily life and include images of school children, views of classrooms, school athletic events and athletic teams, street scenes, offices, businesses, a wedding, and portraits of individuals; also images of Hamtramck's mayor Robert Kozaren with others.
  - Untitled envelope
    - Disrepairs, interior, 3 negatives (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck Chancellors football game, 5 negatives (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck police car, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Immaculate Conception football team, 4 negatives (Box 3)
    - Mayor Robert Kozaren and others, 2 negatives (Box 3)
    - Office scenes, 6 negatives (Box 3)
    - School children, 14 negatives (Box 3)
    - St. Ladislaus basketball game, 4 negatives (Box 3)
    - Store interior (Box 3)
    - Street view (Box 3)
  - Undated loose photographs
    - Bicyclists (Box 3)
    - Classrooms (Box 3)
    - Exterior of building (Box 3)
    - Group photo July 9 1972 (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck Chancellors (Box 3)
    - Hamtramck's 50th anniversary (1972 ?) (Box 3)
    - Landscaping (Box 3)
    - Parked cars (Box 3)
    - St. Ladislaus baseball game (Box 3)
    - Unidentified man (Box 3)
- "Gordie," 1970s-1980s